JESS YOUNG

iess.young2@gmail.com

SUMMARY

For the past 6+ years I've worked with small businesses and start-ups, focusing on scaling organizations through business process optimization and database design & management. I love using my analytical skills to improve the flow of data between different teams and help organizations work more cohesively.

I've worked as the primary architect and administrator for a 150+ user Salesforce environment, including Visualforce and Apex development. I'm also a certified Dell Boomi Professional Developer with experience building custom integrations between CRM, financial and construction management platforms.

I care about living my life with minimal negative impact to the environment and prioritize working with mission based organizations committed to sustainability.

KNOWLEDGE

Database Design Process Automation
Salesforce API Integration
FinancialForce Dell Boomi
Quickbooks Quickbase

Procore Project Management

EDUCATION

Northwestern University Evanston, USA *Postgraduate Researcher: 2012 – 2013*

Post-graduate studies in physical chemistry. The focus of my research was understanding the reactions of organic aerosol particles in the atmosphere, and their consequences in climate change. I was a teaching assistant in an Organic Chemistry laboratory course and mentored undergraduate students pursuing careers in sciences.

McGill University Montreal, Canada

B.Sc. in Chemistry, First Class Honors: 2007 - 2011

GPA: 3.64/4.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bright Power, Inc. New York, USA

Systems and Integration Specialist: January 2019 - Present Operations Associate: January 2017 - December 2018

Engineering Operations Administrator: May 2015 - December 2016

Bright Power is an engineering consulting firm that helps buildings save energy. My primary role on the Technology Operations team is to build internal tools, systems and integrations to streamline business processes and help our employees work smarter together.

- Designing and building custom integrations for Quickbooks, Salesforce, Procore and T-Sheets, primarily using Dell Boomi, in order to ensure smooth operations and flow of data between different departments of the company.
- Managing 150+ user Salesforce environment, including driving Lightning transition, developing in Visualforce and Apex, and implementation of Salesforce Site external user portal.
- Overhauling the Accounts Receivable process to minimize manual data entry and integrate our financial data directly within our project management/CRM system, resulting in a 30% increase in collections.
- Optimizing team workflow while building a new tracking system for energy audits of hundreds of buildings across New York City, and thousands of benchmarking compliance submissions nationwide.

Sóijen

Co-founder: January 2017 - Present

At Sóijen we promote off-the-beaten-path areas in Patagonia through our unique products & designs. As Co-founder my role involves wearing many hats — from web design and content creation to vendor selection & management and financial planning & tracking.

Zomato Chile, SpA. Santiago, Chile

Operations Manager: August 2014 – March 2015 Content Associate: April 2014 – August 2014

Zomato is a website and app that helps users discover new restaurants. In Santiago, Chile we built a database of 8500+ restaurants from the ground up. As Operations Manager for this fast growing start-up, I focused on growing our team and developing standardized processes.

Turismo Paisaje Austral

Office Manager & Guide: November 2013 – January 2014

Turismo Paisaje Austral is a tourism agency located in the heart of Chilean Patagonia. I focused on day to day office management, sales, translation of company website to English, and enthusiastically introducing tourists from all over the world to Chilean Patagonia.

LANGUAGES

English	****
Spanish	****
Japanese	**
French	*